Department of Justice Investigative Files on Industrial Workers of the World, Part 1 on Microfilm 5863 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- RG 60 - Straight Numerical File (Reel 9)
  - 0684. F.W. Henshaw. Case File 188044. 66 pages., 1917; 8 (Reel 9)
    People: F.W. Henshaw; Frank K. Nebeker; Thomas W. Gregory; William C. Fitts; J. C. Thompson; Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; Charles M. Fickert; John W. Preston; A. B. Bielaski. Subjects: Supreme Court of California Justice F.W. Henshaw allegations regarding Industrial Workers of the World activities in California; investigation of explosion at Mare Island, California, Navy Yard; Mooney-Billings case; district attorney for the city and county of San Francisco, California, public relations activities; International Workers' Defense League; United States Department of Labor cooperation with Department of Justice; immigration and naturalization cases.
  - 0750. Fresno, California, Industrial Workers of the World Case. Case File 188561. 113 pages., 1917-1922; 9 (Reel 9)
    People: Annette Abbott Adams; J. Edgar Hoover; Claude R. Porter; Elmer Anderson; J. Robert O'Connor; John W. Preston; Thomas W. Gregory; William C. Fitts. Subjects: Prison conditions at Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary; partial transcript of trial and indictment in case against Elmer Anderson, et al.; Department of Justice prosecution of Fresno an Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World defendants and Chicago, Illinois, prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World leadership; Industrial Workers of the World organization of agricultural workers and acts of sabotage in California.
  - 0863. C. W. Anderson, et al. Case File 189152. Section 1. 267 pages., 1917-1919; 10 (Reel 9)
    People: C.W. Anderson; Albert DeSilver; Claude R. Porter; Fred Robertson; Thomas W. Gregory; John Lord O'Brian; George N. Murdock; George F. Vanderveer; Oliver E. Pagan; Frank K. Nebeker; William C. Fitts; A. B. Bielaski; Charles F. Clyne. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Wichita, Kansas; investigation of Industrial Workers of the World organization of oil field workers and agricultural workers; Industrial Workers of the World publications; National Civil Liberties Bureau; Department of Justice policies regarding bail for Industrial Workers of the World defendants; United States War Department cooperation with Department of Justice; indictment and complaint in case against C. W. Anderson, et al.; internment of aliens during World War I.
- RG 60 - Straight Numerical File (Reel 10)
  - 0000. C. W. Anderson, et al. Case File 189152. Section 2. 201 pages., 1919; 1 (Reel 10)
    People: C.W. Anderson; A. Mitchell Palmer; Fred Robertson; Claude R. Porter; Oliver E. Pagan; John C. Pollock; George F. Vanderveer; Albert DeSilver; William C. Herron; John Lord O'Brian; Alfred Bettman; William L. Frierson. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Wichita, Kansas, citizen protests against Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants; decision and order of Judge Pollock regarding the return of Industrial Workers of the World documents seized by the Department of Justice, indictment, petition for return of papers, and motion to quash indictment, demurrer, and motion for bill of particulars in case against C. W. Anderson, et al.; Industrial Workers of the World organization of oil field workers and agricultural workers; Industrial Workers of the World publications; Industrial Workers of the World legal defense efforts; Department of Justice raids in Kansas, Oklahoma, and Minnesota; National Civil Liberties Bureau; Department of Justice policies regarding bail for Industrial Workers of the World defendants; prison conditions of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners held in the county jails of Kansas.
  - 0201. C. W. Anderson, et al. Case File 189152. Section 3. 235 pages., 1919-1921; 2 (Reel 10)
    People: C.W. Anderson; James M. Beck; Harry M. Daugherty; Fred Robertson; Robert P. Stewart; F.W. Galbraith, Jr.; Annette Abbott Adams; Samuel B. Amidon; George F. Vanderveer; A. Mitchell Palmer; Fred H. Moore; Caroline A. Lowe; J. Edgar Hoover; John C. Pollock; John H. Atwood; Frank J. Silsbee; Louis F. Post; Alexander Howat. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Wichita, Kansas; United States Supreme Court denial of writ of certiorari, United States Circuit Court of Appeals decision, motion for severance, and ruling of Judge Pollock on motion to quash indictment in case against C. W. Anderson, et al.; American Legion; internment of aliens during World War I; Industrial Workers of the World publications; Industrial Workers of the World organization of oil field workers and agricultural workers; Industrial Workers of the World legal defense efforts; United States Department of Labor cooperation with Department of Justice; union protests against Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World members.
  - 0436. C. W. Anderson, et al. Case File 189152. Section 2 and 3. Previously Restricted Materials. 21 pages., 1919-1921; 3 (Reel 10)
    People: C.W. Anderson; J. Edgar Hoover; Claude R. Porter. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendant in Wichita, Kansas; Bureau of Investigation.
  - 0457. Spokane, Washington. Case File 189738. 13 pages., 1917-1918; 4 (Reel 10)
    People: Thomas W. Gregory; John Lord O'Brian; A. B. Bielaski; Claude R. Porter; William C. Fitts. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Spokane, Washington; Industrial Workers of the World strikes; private detective agencies.
  - 0470. Seattle, Washington. Case File 193498. 29 pages., 1918-1919; 5 (Reel 10)
    People: Thomas W. Gregory; Robert C. Saunders; Clarence L. Reames; Claude R. Porter; John Lord O'Brian. Subjects: Alleged illegal arrests and false imprisonment of Industrial Workers of the World members by special agents of the Department of Justice, United States Navy personnel, and local officials in Seattle, Washington; Office of Naval Intelligence; Seattle District Defense Committee and General Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World.
  - 0499. Butte, Montana. Case File 195397. Section 1. 143 pages., 1918-1920; 6 (Reel 10)
    People: J. Edgar Hoover; Baldwin Robertson; A. Mitchell Palmer; Edward C. Day; S.V. Stewart; Burton K. Wheeler; Robert P. Stewart; John Lord O'Brian; Victor Elting; Thomas W. Gregory; Newton D. Baker; A. B. Bielaski. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World and radical activities in Montana; citizen and United States congressman protests against Butte, Montana, Daily Bulletin editorials regarding Industrial Workers of the World union organization, violence in labor disputes, and free speech; use of United States Guards in Butte, Montana, labor disputes; Espionage Act prosecutions; general strikes; American Protective League; governor of Montana requests for federal intervention in Butte, Montana; private detective agencies; United States War Department cooperation with Department of Justice; alleged illegal arrests and false imprisonments by United States Guard and local officials in Butte, Montana.
  - 0642. Butte, Montana. Case File 195397. Section 1. Previously Unrestricted Materials. 69 pages., 1918-1920; 7 (Reel 10)
    People: Baldwin Robertson; J. Edgar Hoover; A. Mitchell Palmer; A.B. Bielaski. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World and radical activities in Montana; citizen protests against editorials and state prosecution of editors of the Butte, Montana, Daily Bulletin; American Loyalty League; general strikes; use of United States Guards in Butte, Montana, labor disputes; alleged illegal arrests and false imprisonments by United States Guards and local officials in Butte, Montana.
  - 0711. Butte, Montana. Case File 195397. Section 2. 56 pages., 1920; 8 (Reel 10)
    People: Baldwin Robertson; A. Mitchell Palmer. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World and radical activities in Montana; contempt of court and improper use of mail charges brought against editors of the Butte, Montana, Daily Bulletin; private detective agencies; violence in labor disputes; immigration and deportation cases.
  - 0767. Butte, Montana. Case File 195397. Section 2. Previously Restricted Materials. 45 pages., 1920; 9 (Reel 10)
    People: Baldwin Robertson; Robert P. Stewart; J. Edgar Hoover; A.S. Embree; Nicholas Radivoeff. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World and radical activities in Montana; immigration and deportation cases; investigation and prosecution of Butte, Montana, Daily Bulletin editorials and use of mail; United States Post Office Department cooperation with Department of Justice; Bureau of Investigation report on Industrial Workers of the World activities in Butte, Montana.
  - 0812. Butte, Montana. Case File 195397. Subsection 1. 52 pages., 1920; 10 (Reel 10)
    People: Baldwin Robertson; A. Mitchell Palmer; Frank K. Nebeker; Robert P. Stewart; J. Edgar Hoover; Louis F. Post; William L. Frierson. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World and radical activities in Montana; Espionage Act prosecutions; Butte, Montana, Daily Bulletin; American Legion; United States Department of Labor cooperation with Department of Justice.
  - 0864. Butte, Montana. Case File 195397. Subsection 2. 6 pages., 1920; 11 (Reel 10)
    People: Baldwin Robertson. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World and radical activities in Montana; alleged false affidavits made by managing editor of the Butte, Montana, Daily Bulletin.
  - 0870. James H. Rowan. Case File 210791. 178 pages., 1920-1927; 12 (Reel 10)
    People: James H. Rowan; Oscar R. Luhring; John G. Sargent; Charles F. Clyne; Roy C. Fox; John Marshall; J. Edgar Hoover; Donald F. Kizer; Edwin A. Olson; Roy A. Darling; H.S. Ridgely; Henry S. Huntington; Harlan F. Stone; Frank R. Jeffrey; Harry M. Daugherty; William C. Herron; Robert P. Stewart; Theodore G. Risley; Annette Abbott Adams; Louis F. Post; T. J. Spellacy. Subjects: Naturalization and immigration case involving convicted Industrial Workers of the World leader, whose sentence had been commuted; United States Department of Labor cooperation with Department of Justice; decision of United States Circuit Court of Appeals overturning decree cancelling certificate of naturalization; citizen and United States congressman protests against cancellation of citizenship of James H. Rowan.
- RG 204 - Pardon Attorney Files (Reel 11)
  - 0001. Charles Ashleigh. Case File 35-362. 393 pages., 1919-1922; 1 (Reel 11)
    People: Charles Ashleigh; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty; James A. Finch; Harry Weinberger; George B. Christian; Jr.; Frank K. Nebeker; Elizabeth Gurley Flynn; Alexander S. Lanier; Mary Heaton Vorse; Robert H. Turner; Charles F. Clyne; A. Mitchell Palmer; Woodrow W. Wilson; Frank L. Polk. Subjects: Application for executive clemency in behalf of Charles Ashleigh; appeals, reports, and exhibits supporting applications; Workers' Defense Union; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; deportations; amnesty proposals in the United States Congress; amnesty laws in England, Canada, Italy, Belgium, and France; Espionage Act convictions; Industrial Workers of the World publications.
  - 0394. Carl Ahlteen, Ragner Johanson, and Sigfried Stenberg. Case File 36-52. 293 pages., 1921-1933; 2 (Reel 11)
    People: Carl Ahlteen; Ragner Johanson; Sigfried Stenberg; James A. Finch; Lucille B. Milner; Harry M. Daugherty; Roger N. Baldwin; Charles Evans Hughes; Axel Wallenberg; A. Mitchell Palmer; Charles F. Clyne; Robert H. Turner; John Lord O'Brian; Morris L. Ernst; Arthur Garfield Hays; William D. Mitchell; Herbert C. Hoover; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Warren G. Harding; Mary Gertrude Fendall. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency in behalf of Carl Ahlteen, Ragner Johanson, and Sigfried Stenberg; appeals, reports, and exhibits supporting applications; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; deportations; American Civil Liberties Union; Industrial Workers of the World publications; Espionage Act convictions; amnesty proposals in the United States Congress; Joint Amnesty Committee.
  - 0686. So-called Political Prisoner Cases. No Case File Number. 75 pages., 1921-1923; 3 (Reel 11)
    People: Vincent St. John. Subjects: Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; general amnesty proposals in the United States and abroad; lists of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States and summaries of cases; Espionage Act convictions.
  - 0761. Charles L. Lambert, Sam Scarlett, and Aurelio V. Azuara. Case File 38-487. 284 pages., 1921-1923; 4 (Reel 11)
    People: Charles L. Lambert; Sam Scarlett; Aurelio V. Azuara; Archibald R. Sinclair; Harry M. Daugherty; Warren G. Harding; James A. Finch; Charles F. Clyne; John Lord O'Brian; Newton D. Baker; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Mary Gertrude Fendall. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Charles L. Lambert, Sam Scarlett, and Aurelio V. Azuara; appeals, reports, and exhibits supporting applications; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; deportations; general amnesty proposals; Joint Amnesty Committee; American Civil Liberties Union; lists of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Industrial Workers of the World publications and union organization; Espionage Act convictions.
- RG 204 - Pardon Attorney Files (Reel 12)
  - 0001. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. General. 276 pages., 1921-1924; 1 (Reel 12)
    People: Harry M. Daugherty; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Newton D. Baker; Warren F. Martin; Mary Gertrude Fendall; John C. Pollock; Edward Anderson; C.W. Anderson; Elmer Anderson; James A. Finch; Augustus T. Seymour; E.J. Henning; Harry F. Ward; Roger N. Baldwin; Charles F. Clyne; Claude R. Porter; Pierce C. Wetter. Subjects: General amnesty proposals; Espionage Act convictions; lists of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Joint Amnesty Committee; American Civil Liberties Union; appeals, reports, and exhibits supporting applications; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; deportations; partial transcript on appeal of case against Edward Anderson, et al.; Industrial Workers of the World publications; Wichita, Kansas, and Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World cases; General Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World.
  - 0277. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (A). Bennett, Charles. 26 pages., 1921-1929; 2 (Reel 12)
    People: Charles Bennett; George Wharton Pepper; Augustus T. Seymour; James A. Finch. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; general amnesty proposals in the United States; Espionage Act convictions.
  - 0303. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (B). Bourg, G. J.. 20 pages., 1922-1925; 3 (Reel 12)
    People: G.J. Bourg; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty; Charles F. Clyne. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency in behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; deportations; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0323. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (C). Brazier, Richard. 47 pages., 1922-1925; 4 (Reel 12)
    People: Richard Brazier; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty; Charles F. Clyne; Pierce C. Wetter; William E. Borah. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; deportations; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World convictions; New York branch office of the General Defense Committee.
  - 0370. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (D). Chaplin, Ralph. 24 pages., 1922-1923; 5 (Reel 12)
    People: Ralph Chaplin; James A. Finch; Robert T. Kerlin; Warren G. Harding; Mabel Walker Willebrandt; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency in behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; censorship of mail of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners at Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0394. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (E). Cournos, Alexander. 10 pages., 1923; 6 (Reel 12)
    People: Alexander Cournos. Subjects: Applications for clemency in behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0404. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (F). Davis, C.W.. 10 pages., 1923; 7 (Reel 12)
    People: C.W. Davis; C.H. Rice. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0414. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (G). Doran, J.T.. 7 pages., 1923; 8 (Reel 12)
    People: J. T. Doran. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0421. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (H). Edwards, Forrest. 5 pages., 1923; 9 (Reel 12)
    People: Forrest Edwards. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0426. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (I) Foss, John. 8 pages., 1923; 10 (Reel 12)
    People: John Foss. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0434. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (J) Graber, Joe. 5 pages., 1923; 11 (Reel 12)
    People: Joe Graber. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World.
  - 0439. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (K) Green, Peter. 12 pages., 1922-1923; 12 (Reel 12)
    People: Peter Green; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty; Charles F. Clyne. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0451. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (L). Kane, H.F.. 7 pages., 1923; 13 (Reel 12)
    People: H.F. Kane; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners and censorship of mail.
  - 0458. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (M). Lloyd, Harry. 8 pages., 1923-1925; 14 (Reel 12)
    People: Harry Lloyd; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; deportations; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.
  - 0466. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (N). Lorton, Burt. 12 pages., 1922-1925; 15 (Reel 12)